There's a new way to predict the
weather, and it seems to be much better.
So, your weather app right now probably
uses measurements from all over the
world of wind and pressure and
temperature and plugs them into super
complicated physics equations. The
problem is a single forecast can take
trillions of [music] calculations. So,
they're only great at predicting either
where the storm will go or how intense
it'll get. But, this new model learns by
looking at a bunch of historical data,
both of measured weather in the past and
of previous cyclones. And that data,
paired with satellite imagery, helps it
find patterns in how weather develops.
And it's now better than traditional
methods at both predicting the path and
the intensity. So much so, that we could
get the same level of accuracy a full
day earlier. [music] But, we know that
this year half the world's weather
system is about to break. So, to see
why, subscribe.